EVAN DANA

Sr. Software Engineer Boston, MA

☑ evan.writes.code@gmail.com

n @evandana

in evandana

evandana com

LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER WITH A FOCUS ON ARCHITECTING SUCCESSFUL WEB AND MOBILE EXPERIENCES. Specializing in front-end technologies, I deliver customer value through leadership and collaborative roles: as an individual contributor, technical lead, and counsel for stakeholders. I enjoy providing technical mentorship and plan to stay current with tools and patterns. I approach challenges with engaging energy and passion.

Work History

Pear Therapeutics

Sr. Software Engineer

React Native, React-Native-Testing-Library, TypeScript, Bitrise.io

2019 - Present | Boston, MA

Worked across multiple prescription digital therapeutic (PDT) apps (iOS / Android) and the mobile platform team in a variety of capacities from individual contributor to Tech Lead. Followed the engineering practices of Software as a Medical Device (SaMD), ensuring high quality and auditable code while also focusing on value-based delivery.

- Tech Lead
- · Mobile Platform
- · Chair of Employee Engagement Council

General Electric | GE Digital

Sr. Software Engineer

ES6, Polymer, WebSockets, NodeJS, CI/CD, Agile, Domain Modeling, Docker, AngularJS, ProUI, Bash scripting, Markdown documentation

2016 - 2019 | Boston, MA

Publicis.Sapient |

Sr. Interactive Developer, L2

2013 - 2016 | Boston, MA

Sapient Consulting

ES6, D3.js, AngularJS, Aurelia, Agile, JSPM,

Development, Domain Modeling, JIRA

Node, IS, Continuous Integration, Hexagonal Architecture (server-side), Domain-Driven

Delivered complex features in a timely manner, independently and through collaboration, with utmost attention to quality. Exemplified best practices from coding patterns to agile methodologies. Translated requirements into manageable stories with clear and complete acceptance criteria, raising discussions early if needed. Ensured quality by writing unit and system tests for use in CI/CD workflow. Consistently $\,$ created useful graphical and text-based documentation. Exposed to varied project architecture elements including cloud, microapp/microservices, and Docker.

Mentored software engineers and presented on modern UI frameworks and patterns through the use of interactive programming session.

UI lead and front-end developer with aptitude for team dynamics, group coordination, and process efficiencies.

Awarded recognition for Client-Focused Delivery after client feedback on project when leading UI development with recently self-taught technology.

Years of experience in UI lead role, conducting engaging presentations, and as technical liaison for client and internal domain teams. Enforced code quality using best practices such as John DePapa's style guide and BEM on Agile projects. Self-motivated and driven: exemplified by creation of D3.js library and initiation of effective team-building program. Advocated for code stability through unit, integration, functional, or automated visual-diff testing.

planning tool, turning complex business logic into an engaging user

- Community thought leader and advocate
- · Feature lead
- · Team contributor
- · Independent feature delivery
- · Backlog refinement and feature design

· Autonomous and motivated

· Quickly learned and utilized new technology

Putnam Investments

Javascript UI Developer

JavaScript (jQuery, Highcharts), CSS, HTML, Backbone.js, Modernizr, SVN

2012 - 2013 | Boston, MA

Implemented significant contributions to interactive retirement

Initiated suite of unit tests to prevent recurring defects. Reached crossbrowser functionality with collaborative discussions.

- · Drove consistent quality with unit test suite
- · Created dynamic visualizations for retirement income projections

Innerscope Research Inc.

2009 - 2012 | Boston, MA

HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, Photoshop, Illustrator

Code Highlights

Non-profit Intake App

https://github.com/evandana/keep-ahope

ReactJS 15.1.x, Redux, Google Cloud, Parse, WebSockets, Material-UI, Google OAuth, ES6, Babel, Open source, GitHub Projects

2018 - Present

Leading a team to create an patient intake app for a local non-profit. with guidance from GE Foundation. Creating and navigating requirements from business stakeholders, including secure data storage and transfer with Google Cloud Platform. Bringing together experts (domain, UX, legal, medical, technical) and driving consensus. Managing a small group of software engineers who are donating time for this project: ensuring coordinated efforts, timely delivery, and continued engagement. Utilizing GitHub projects to achieve agile development, stay focused on MVP and keep stakeholders informed.

- · Form submission, profile search, profile update, and aggregation reports
- Websockets and REST
- Data architecture: Redux
- · Secure sign-in using Google OAuth
- Parse API for server and database interface on Google Cloud

PMC Auction App

2016 - 2018

ReactJS 15.1.x, Redux, WebSockets, Firebase.io, Material-UI, Google OAuth, ES6, Babel, Domain Modeling, Trello, ESLint, Webpack

Education History

Rochester Institute of Technology

Bachelor, Industrial Design

2001 – 2005 | Rochester, NY

Harvard Extension School

Mobile Operating Systems and Applications

2013 – 2013 | Cambridge, MA

Coursera.org

2012 – 2013 | Stanford University Online

Activities

D3.js Instructor

General Assembly

2015 | Boston, MA